Well, our game is coming together quite nicely.
Now we need to do is introduce the objective to the game, which obviously is to try and catch this
ladybug.
Because right now, if we touch the ladybug, nothing really happens.
But what we want to happen is to have the ladybug vanish and have our dragonfly say yum, and maybe
play a pop sound like it's been eaten.
So let's start off with our dragonfly.
I want you to try and get it to say yum or whatever you like, but get it to say something when it touches
the ladybug.
See if you can do that.
Pause this video.
Give it a go.
Can you get the dragonfly to say something when it touches the ladybug?
Let's think about this.
We'll need a sensing block to sense that the sprite is touching another.
And we can use this one here.
Now clicking on here, we can change the touching sense from mouse pointer to ladybug two.
Then, just like with our arrow clicks, we are going to need an if conditional block and a forever
loop.
Then we need to say hello for two seconds.
Block to get it to say what we want when it touches the ladybug.
Oh, and there's also one more thing we need this play sound pop block.
So just like before, we can organize our script so that it forever checks if it is touching the ladybug,
and if so, we will have it say yum and then play the pop sound.
Now.
If we play it now, you will see when we now touch the ladybug.
If I can touch it.
Oh, there we go.
It says yum and plays the pop sound.
Now one thing I can do to improve this is to play the pop sound first, then say yum for two seconds.
Uh, this just makes it more seamless.
Okay, cool.
So our game is almost there.
And before we move on to program the ladybug, I just want to point something out because you might
be wondering why we have two separate scripts here.
Like, why don't we just put this piece of code inside here?
So we just have one script?
Well, if you were wondering that.
Good wondering.
Good question.
Well, let's try it.
So adding it in and now clicking play you will see that now when we touch the ladybug if I can touch
it.
There you go.
But notice how suddenly I can no longer control the dragonfly.
It just like freezes.
Why is this?
Well, if we look at our script logically, taking the code out again.
Look, this is all a loop, so we are constantly checking if any of these conditions are true and if
one of them is true.
Like we click the down arrow, it goes down.
But remember how I said code runs from the top down?
Well, that is happening here.
So when we click start it's going to check if the right arrow has been pressed.
Then it's going to check if the left arrow is being pressed, then the up then the down.
So it's not really checking all these conditions at the same time.
It's going from the top down.
But because it happened so fast, it seems like it's checking it all at the same time.
However, if I were to add a wait one second like to this, check for the down arrow.
Notice how our other arrows work perfectly, but as soon as it checks for the down arrow, all the other
arrows freeze up.
And this is because it's running the code from the top down.
And when it gets to this code, it needs to wait for a second.
And it can only continue the loop once the second is over.
So basically that is why this code has the same problem.
Because there is this say yum for two seconds and it will only continue looping the code once it is
finished executing the script.
So that is one of the reasons we use another script, so we can have multiple things running at the
same time without any issue.
Now I could take out this, say yum for two seconds and add it back into the loop.
Look, if we play it again, you'll see it works and it doesn't freeze.
But even if you just wanted our sprite to play a sound, you should still use a separate script for
this.
Basically, having separate scripts is just so much better for keeping things organized.
You see, when you make really big programs, really big gains, things can get quite confusing.
And if you have just one ultra mega long script, you might not know what's going on.
So what we suggest is that each script you have should do just one thing.
Remember that each script should just do one thing.
This script controls the arrow keys.
This one checks if we're touching the ladybug, and if you are well organized like this from the start,
you'll be really thankful in the future when you make some fun and really complex games.
So with that, there's just one more thing to code for our game to be complete, and that is getting
the ladybug to disappear when it touches the dragonfly.
Try to give this challenge a shot and see if you can do it on your own.
Otherwise, I'll see you in the next lesson and show you how it can be done.